## **BENJAMIN YOMTOV**

Phone: 908-448-6633 | Email: <u>benyomtov@comcast.net</u> | Easton, PA | LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/benyomtov/ | Portfolio: https://benyomtov.github.io/react-portfolio |

Github: https://github.com/benyomtov

Highly motivated Front-End Web Developer with a background in social sciences and previous experience as an English tutor for students struggling with reading comprehension. Possesses excellent attention to detail, a creative problem-solving approach, and exceptional time management skills. Demonstrates a natural talent for collaborating with teams to develop innovative solutions to complex problems. Earned a certificate in Full Stack Web Development from the Rutgers University Coding Bootcamp.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

JavaScript, CSS, HTML, MySQL, NoSQL, Github, MongoDB, Express, React, Node, Handlebars, JQuery, Bootstrap, GraphQL

#### **PROJECTS**

## LightBox | Github

**Summary:** Front-end drawing application that provides users with an engaging platform for expressing their creativity and imagination.

Role: Sole Author

Tools: React, Canvas API, Google Fonts, Bootstrap, React Icons, React Draggable

## **Quit Smoking App | Github**

Summary: Full-stack web application that helps users to quit smoking cigarettes over a period of

time

Role: Backend Developer/CSS

Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Handlebars, Express, Node.js, Heroku, Chart.js

## Weekly Calendar | Github

**Summary:** Front-end calendar application designed to help the user stay motivated and organize tasks throughout the work week.

Role: JavaScript/APIs

Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MDBootstrap, OpenWeather API, Day.js

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Certificate in Full Stack Web Development**

Rutgers University Nov 2022 - Feb 2023

## Associate's Degree in Social Sciences

Raritan Valley Community College Oct 2018 - Dec 2022

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## English Tutor May 2022 - Oct 2022 Lindamood-Bell Learning Processes Morristown, NJ

- ★ Provided one-to-one language arts instruction based upon each student's individual learning needs.
- ★ Worked with Center Director, Associate Center Director, and Educational Consultant to implement client lesson plans.
- ★ Interacted professionally with clients and staff to provide a safe and positive learning environment.
- ★ Recognized for outstanding contributions as an English tutor with the "Most Likely to Get Students Moving" award from Lindamood-Bell Learning Processes.

# Delivery Driver Roman Gourmet August 2021 - March 2022 Hillsborough, NJ

- ★ Safely operated and maintained delivery vehicles to deliver pizza orders to customers in a timely and efficient manner.
- ★ Ensured prompt and accurate delivery of orders while providing excellent customer service.
- ★ Maintained cleanliness and organization of the restaurant by performing regular cleaning duties, including sweeping, mopping, and sanitizing surfaces.
- ★ Assisted with counter service, including taking orders and handling cash and credit card transactions.
- ★ Provided courteous and attentive service to customers dining in the restaurant.

## Customer Service Associate March 2020 - March 2021 Dollar Tree Hillsborough, NJ

- ★ Responsible for stocking shelves, merchandising, and upkeep/maintenance of the store.
- ★ Responsible for cashiering, meeting and greeting customers, resolving customer complaints, general bookkeeping, answering phone calls, helping customers find items they are looking for in the store, and answering other questions for customers.